What took you so long?
- Hyeon-guk, get the fire going.
- Eun-jung!
- Grab a new one.
- We're firing up the grill.
Let's talk for a second.
You can start eating without us.
Kim Sang-hak, you're supposed to grill!
Where are you going?
This letter is adorable.
Is this why you were crying?
Because it brought up old memories?
I just felt bad
seeing Ms. Yoon like that.
Since Sang-yeon and I reconnected,
we haven't had a chance
to really talk about her brother.
I did ask her about him once though.
There must be people
who knew him in the past
who are still unaware that he's gone.
They must think that
he's somewhere, alive and well.
It's like that for me too.
He never even crosses my mind.
I figured it was her way of coping,
but seeing her behavior
towards Ms. Yoon today…
I really don't get it.
You felt it too, right?
She deliberately took us there
to hurt Ms. Yoon's feelings.
That's why…
I couldn't stand to look at her earlier.
What did she tell you?
Did she not say anything?
I'm not sure,
but she seemed pretty shaken up herself.
Why do something that's just going to
weigh on your own mind?
Sang-yeon's brother…
What happened to him?
It was suicide.
But I don't know why.
Sang-yeon told me that
Ms. Yoon disapproved of his girlfriend.
The night before he left…
I slept over at Sang-yeon's place.
In the middle of the night, he suddenly
offered to teach me how to use a camera.
Eun-jung.
Yes?
One second.
Now that I think about it,
it was an odd thing to do.
He was acting strange
in more ways than one that day…
but I missed all the signs.
Like an idiot.
Do you actually think it would have made
a difference if you'd caught on?
That's just not true.
That clover…
The clover?
The gift from your father? What about it?
My dad is…
He's dead.
I gave him something…
from someone who was dead.
Hey, that's absurd.
Come here.
Everyone, eat up before it burns.
What's taking them so long?
I know, right?
Did they have an argument or something?
- No.
- Here they come.
Where on earth have you been?
Get a move on already.
Man, I'm the best at grilling.
- You should've hurried, then.
- Come on, show us your skills.
Hey, mosquito alert.
Wait, were you crying?
Oppa, did you make her cry?
It's not like that.
Forget it and eat up. Open up.
How is it?
It's so good.
You heard her.
Your girlfriend says it's good.
- Duh, I grilled it.
- Do you guys even know good meat?
- It's burning.
- My bad.
- Flip that one.
- This one?
YOU AND EVERYTHING ELSE
I'll take that. You take the smaller ones.
Take that fan instead.
- Is it heavy?
- Very.
All the stuff's moved in.
Shall we get to organizing?
This room could have been a tad bigger.
I told her to take the bigger room,
but she's so stubborn.
- Sang-yeon.
- Yeah?
Ms. Yoon's calling.
- Trust me. This is it.
- I got my workout for the day.
See? We're in the right place.
Hey!
- This place is great.
- Hi!
Cheers!
Don't even think about crashing here
after a night of drinking.
You two, don't ever let them in.
Of course we won't.
If we come knocking,
she'll welcome us with open arms.
- Really?
- And you'll be in the military anyway.
Don't bring up the m-word.
- I got a military exemption.
- You mentioned it again!
- Hi, Jeong-seon!
- Hi!
Here she is, the loyal one.
Eun-jung, meet your future.
She's been flying solo since Kyu-ho left
for the military a month ago.
Jeong-seon, what's it like sending
your boyfriend off to the military?
When's he leaving?
In six days.
You must be clueless as of now.
Enjoy your last moments, you two.
You're not planning on sticking around
at home all day, are you?
Sorry?
You need to give them some space
so they can be all lovey-dovey.
Hey, what are you…
Right.
Don't worry about us.
"Don't worry about us."
We're out of drinks.
- I'll go buy some.
- Me too.
Where are you two going?
Off to sneak a kiss?
Just a kiss?
What?
- Man, he's a total pervert.
- I'm cringing so hard.
Kyu-ho asked me to send him
an electric watch.
An electric watch?
Yeah. Not an expensive one
but a simple, black one.
- Do you know what that is?
- Yeah, they're…
Still unpacking?
Yeah. Just a bit.
Drinking wasn't the plan,
but they just showed up.
Sleep and finish tomorrow.
I will. Are you going to bed?
- Yeah.
- Good night.
You too.
Feel free to let me know.
You know, before he enlists…
I told you it's not like that.
Just tell me if you need to.
Instead of that,
let's get our stories straight.
- Stories?
- We're going on a trip in two days.
I'm worried Mom might find out.
This trip is with you, okay?
Where are you going?
Gapyeong. Just for one night,
so we can't go anywhere far.
I got you.
Thanks.
What's this?
Get in.
Are we taking this car? Look at this.
It's my dad's.
I've never seen you drive before.
Get in. We'll give you a ride to school.
I'm good. Go have fun. You too.
I'll drive you.
No, thanks.
Seonbae.
You look so cool driving.
Really?
You're all silent and serious.
What are you thinking about?
Dirty thoughts.
Dirty thoughts? As if!
I bet you're too focused on driving.
When I'm with you,
my mind's always in the gutter.
That reminds me.
Sang-yeon told me to let her know
if we want the house to ourselves.
Wow, however did she come up with
such a great idea?
I would gladly leave the house for her
every single day if she were dating.
- She doesn't want to date?
- It's not that.
She mentioned having a crush on someone
who she met online back in Gangneung.
Online?
It's unlike her, isn't it?
She said the feelings weren't mutual.
Have you ever met someone
in an online chat room?
You think?
I thought not.
- Give me a hand.
- Here.
Wait.
- Hey!
- Let's go!
Are you ready?
You fall, you lose, okay?
Don't get too hung up on winning.
I used to deliver milk.
I can even ride hands-free.
And the loser has to grant a wish.
Jeez, you sure talk a lot.
Ready, go!
Hey, you cheater!
Did you want to win that bad?
Of course. The prize was a wish.
So what's your wish?
Brace yourself.
Go on, then. I'll grant you any wish.
When I get discharged…
let's come back here.
What? That's your wish?
Yes.
What, you think I can't wait
two years for you?
I never imagined I'd feel this way,
but enlisting certainly sends you
on an emotional roller coaster.
You're so silly.
I like you so much.
- I need to go in now.
- Don't skip your meals.
- Take care, okay?
- Okay.
I'll be in touch.
Thanks for coming.
Take care on your way back.
- Yes, sir!
- Call when you're on leave.
I'll go now.
- Father, I'm going in!
- I'm off.
You got this!
- Write to us!
- Goodbye!
See you.
- I'm going in.
- See you.
- Bye.
- I'm off.
FROM PRIVATE KIM SANG-HAK
TO RYU EUN-JUNG
3 MONTHS LATER
Hey.
You have a letter from Sang-hak.
It's here with the electricity bill.
A letter?
Hello, Ms. Yoon.
Sang-yeon?
She stepped outside for a moment
but must have left her phone.
I'll tell her to call you
as soon as she gets back.
Yes.
Of course. You too, Ms. Yoon.
Goodbye, then.
You heard that, right? Give her a call.
Okay?
I'm going to cook ramyeon. Want some?
Can't you just answer her calls?
Okay, I'm sorry.
I'll tell her to stop calling you.
That's not my point.
Stop calling Eun-jung
whenever you can't reach me.
She says it's annoying.
Whatever. Talk later.
Why did you do that?
You know I didn't say that
because I'm annoyed by her calls.
Then?
Is it that hard for you
to simply answer her calls?
What are you getting at?
You are all she has.
How ridiculous.
Hey.
You think every mother-daughter
relationship out there
is like the one
you have with your mom, don't you?
My mom and I were never meant to be
mother and daughter.
Don't say that.
She said it herself.
I won't ask you to believe me.
Just don't tell me what to do
when you don't know anything.
What would you even know?
What do you actually know?
I hear most moms…
when they lose a child,
try to carry on
for the sake of their other children.
But not my mom.
My mom, she…
You could never understand.
Sang-yeon and I didn't exchange
a single word for the next three days.
It was thanks to Sang-yeon
that I could finally bring myself
to develop that film roll.
My mind was all jumbled because of her,
and I drew strength from the anger.
The first photo was of a quote
from some book.
Then a frame that he had hung in his room.
A photo of Laika the dog.
Some VHS tapes.
The sticker I had placed.
He looked more peaceful
than I had always imagined.
What is this?
Photos that Sang-hak oppa took.
Not Sang-hak seonbae…
but your brother.
My brother?
I've actually had a film roll of his.
I joined the photography club
because I wanted to develop these.
Seeing her sitting there, trembling,
made the three days of silence
and our argument…
feel utterly pointless.
YOU'RE SO LUCKY
DO NOT ENTER
SANG-YEON'S ROOM
I had no clue back then…
just how deeply those photos affected her.
It's her, isn't it?
The woman that he loved.
Why did he die?
I know that it's my fault.
What?
You also think that he died because of me.
Can't you just let them date?
What?
Look. He'll never get over her.
If you keep doing this,
he might really leave home.
Do you mean to say
that he died because of me?
How is that because of me?
It's because of you.
You said yourself that you killed him.
If you hadn't gotten involved,
then he wouldn't have died!
I wouldn't have known
if it weren't for Sang-yeon.
Every single diary entry is about it.
I couldn't…
I couldn't sit back and do nothing.
I only showed you the diary
because I was curious.
Your grown son had found someone he loved,
and I couldn't understand
why you were making such a fuss.
But then…
a week later…
He died one week later.
He died because of me.
No. Sang-yeon, it's not like that.
I didn't know you felt that way.
It's simply not true--
Then tell me!
Tell me what the truth is!
"Your brother died
because of these other reasons,
so it's not your fault."
You need to tell me
so I can live with myself!
It wasn't your fault. It was my fault.
I'll know once I ask her.
I'm going to find this woman,
and I'm going to ask her.
Do you think I can't?
I know someone who knows him very well.
Who…
who knew my Sang-hak that well?
Hi, seonbae.
Are you on leave?
Yeah, my first military leave.
Done for today?
Yes, I'm done for today.
Good, because I was getting bored.
What about Eun-jung?
Tutoring. She'll be here in an hour or so.
Let's hang out and eat together, then.
Sure. But what should we do?
We could go to a café.
Or I was thinking about taking a walk.
- A walk?
- Yeah.
- Where?
- Up that mountain.
I don't really like mountains.
- Should we just go to a café?
- Sure.
Why do you look so down today?
- I do?
- Yeah.
Is it that obvious?
I thought I had a solid poker face.
What's got you feeling down?
Don't say it’s for no reason.
How did you know
I was just about to say that?
Well?
No reason, really.
How about this?
I just
felt like hating Mom today.
Let's leave it at that.
Shall we go for that walk?
Would you like that? All right, then.
Cafés can be stuffy, so a walk is great.
Let’s grab something to drink first.
But
why the sudden change of heart?
What would you like?
My brother
is dead.
I know.
I happened to figure it out,
and Eun-jung told me later.
I'm happy… that you told me yourself.
Could I have a milk tea, please?
Yeah, sure.
All right.
She just got off the subway.
- We'd better hurry, then.
- We'll go slowly but surely.
How have you been?
I'm telling you,
the air is fresher on the outside.
He's so silly.
Listen.
- Here's my list.
- Okay.
McDonald's, pork belly, chicken with beer,
pizza, jjatang.
That's black bean noodles and fried pork.
Ramyeon, Choco Pie, and Coke.
McDonald's comes first?
Yeah. And it has to be a Big Mac with
two patties and three pieces of bread.
Hold up, I already had Choco Pie and Coke.
I ate five in one sitting earlier.
Five?
Sang-yeon!
Cheon Sang-yeon!
I only found out later…
what Sang-hak seonbae…
truly meant to Sang-yeon.
It's on the third floor.
I'll see how it looks.
Sure.
FALL OF 1998
After quitting school
and moving to Gangneung,
Sang-yeon refused to do anything
for a long time.
She never went out,
met people, or spoke to anyone.
The only thing that Sang-yeon did…
was search for four-digit numbers.
GANGWON 81D 2578
Two, five, seven, eight…
INCORRECT PASSWORD
Sang-yeon had once asked her brother
about creating passwords,
and he had replied…
I don't know.
I guess you could use a combination
of four digits and some letters.
She had long forgotten why she was even
trying to log in to his account.
Like any other day, she was trying
different combinations when…
Laika 1957.
INCORRECT PASSWORD
MESSAGE INBOX
INBOX
Why is it so cold in October?
I asked to delay printing the pamphlets,
but everyone says they can't wait.
At this point,
no one believes you'll return.
Even if you show up,
I won't return your tapes.
I'm not sure whether I'm messaging you
out of habit or stubbornness anymore.
My teacher says I might not get in
to university. Isn't that worth a reply?
Moonee? Is it really you? Hey, I--
How could you disappear like that?
Nobody believes me
that you appeared online.
We're having an impromptu meetup
tomorrow at 7:00 p.m. Please come.
You know Jang's Gamjatang, right?
Across the street from Cine Core.
CINE CORE
Come on in.
- Aren't you going to drink something?
- So is he coming or not?
Let's give him some time.
Are you sure he was online?
I'm positive. I messaged him about
our meetup, and he definitely read it.
What would you like?
Pork neck bone soup, please.
Either way, it's a relief. I was worried
something had happened to him.
So let's just wait one more week.
It's not like printing pamphlets
takes long.
Why should we wait for him?
It's not like he was anything special.
He was to Uncle Tat.
You know he respected Moonee.
And what about us?
Moonee needs to come back for his sake.
Don't you need to study for your exams?
I don't get it. He promised he'd come.
He's just some jerk
who let his art go to his head and quit.
Stop making a big fuss.
It's no big deal, okay?
Are you done talking?
Not yet. I haven't even begun.
I wasn't going to say this,
but do you know why
Dylan's been MIA lately?
What does that have to do with Moonee?
- Wait, hey--
- It's because Moonee hit on Dylan.
He acted innocent
but was a two-faced sneak.
Bullshit! Watch your damn mouth!
Watch your mouth, you little prick.
- Cut it out. Sorry, ma'am.
- What is this?
You can dish it out but can't take it?
Just because you hit on everyone
doesn't mean we all do.
Come on, guys!
Cut it out.
Are you okay?
Don't run your mouth
when you know nothing.
Moonee doesn't deserve to be
talked about like that.
Tat, wait.
- That little bastard.
- Drop it.
Hey!
- What's wrong with you kids?
- Sit down.
He was being a prick!
We're sorry, ma'am.
Hey, cool it.
Do you know
what people are saying about you?
That you're some art-obsessed nobody
trying to act relevant
and that Dylan quit
because you did her dirty.
Do you know what I think?
I agree with them.
You're a real coward,
and I won't be writing shit to you again.
This is my last message.
Thank you for…
fighting…
for me.
Hi, Uncle Tat.
I am doing well.
We can't meet right now, but…
I'm…
doing…
really…
From that moment on,
Sang-yeon decided to believe
that her brother was alive somewhere.
REGISTRATION
NICKNAME: SOMEWHERE
FRAME
SEARCH: UNCLETAT
Order number three,
your shrimp burger meal…
Hello.
Introduce yourself now.
I'm a high schooler in Ilyeong.
I'm in high school too.
- Who's finished developing?
- I need another round.
How many rounds has it been already?
Everyone's busy preparing
for the exhibition. Excuse them.
I'm fine. It's fun just to watch.
Well, enjoy.
Is it okay that I don't know much
about photography?
It's my first time joining a club.
UNCLETAT HAS LEFT THE CHAT
UNCLETAT INVITED YOU TO A PRIVATE CHAT
Welcome.
May I take your order?
For drinks, we have Coke and Sprite.
Did you watch the Soonpoong rerun?
I've never watched it. Is it good?
No way. You've never watched
Soonpoong Clinic?
Are you even Korean?
Sorry?
No, I'm good.
I think I should give up
on this year's entrance exams.
Are your grades that bad?
Are you an airhead?
No way. I was just going through a phase.
I'm actually hella smart.
A phase?
There was something more important
than studying.
OFFLINE USERS
UNCLETAT
Let's do this!
I'm officially retaking the exam!
Perhaps he was busy
studying for the entrance exam.
There was no news from Uncle Tat
for a very long time.
Then, one day…
Guys, I'm back!
- Hello.
- Hey!
- Uncle Tat!
- Hey, bro.
- I heard you got in.
Yeongang University, was it? What major?
- Business management.
- Whoa, Kim Sang-hak.
Since when were you smart?
I've always been smart.
- Let's take a photo.
- Sure.
Kim…
Sang-hak.
That's when Sang-yeon decided
that she'd go to university.
It's nice to meet you.
We met at the booth.
I'm Kim Sang-hak, a business major.
I know.
I'm Cheon Sang-yeon.
Engineering. Class of 2002.
Come on, put him in his place.
Your boyfriend's getting cocky again.
These two are dating, by the way.
Wow, really? You guys look good together.
- Do we?
- Yeah.
That hurt my pride.
Honestly, you're not that handsome.
Sang-yeon said it had felt unfair.
Hi, seonbae.
It's been a while since I've smelled this.
The scent of mountains.
It's nice.
Sang-yeon.
I can't
possibly know exactly how you feel,
but I feel like I understand
to some extent, even if just a little.
I'm talking about
being the one left behind.
There was this guy
I was good friends with in the past.
One day, he just vanished.
You can never quite come to terms with it
because you will never know why.
I see.
Were you two very close?
Yes, we were.
Well, I can't speak for him,
but I really liked him as a person.
Do you want this?
What?
A watch?
It was a freebie,
but black isn't really my color.
Wow, I was looking to buy one
exactly like this.
It's a really cheap model,
probably because it was a freebie.
That doesn't matter.
Thanks, seriously.
I needed a watch just like this.
I'm glad it's something you needed.
Sang-yeon realized that day
that she had been in love with him
for a long time
and that she could no longer…
hide her feelings.
Sang-yeon.
Cheon Sang-yeon!
Maybe something's up.
I've never seen her act like that.
Maybe you should head home.
Please enjoy.
It's okay. I'll go check on her later.
This looks good.
- Did you get a new watch?
- Yeah.
Sang-yeon gave it to me.
She got it as a freebie
but didn't like the color.
A mountain?
Yeah, the one behind campus. Why?
It's nothing.
I'm glad.
Glad about what?
Sang-yeon used to be
really afraid of mountains.
Her brother was found on a mountain.
I see.
I also had a place
that I avoided for a long time.
Dajeong Supermarket.
Sang-hak oppa walked me home once,
and we had walked past there.
I couldn't go there for over a year.
I'm sure Sang-yeon
had it much worse than me.
She probably has countless places
that haunt her like that.
Sang-yeon told me today
that her brother died.
She did?
Yeah.
I think it might be a first for her…
opening up to someone about that.
It was probably because I suggested
going up the mountain.
Still, I think it’s great that she got to
share that with someone at all.
But I can't help but feel a little hurt.
I've been patiently waiting for her
to open up to me.
Knowing how painful it must have been,
it's not something I can just bring up.
Maybe it's like this.
I know nothing, so maybe she felt
more comfortable talking to me about it.
Things are different with you.
Perhaps that’s why it's harder for her
to open up to you about it.
Still, I want her to be honest with me.
I want her to tell me
if she's in pain or feeling sad.
Maybe someday, right?
Of course.
By the way, I developed the Tri-X roll.
Really? Let's see it, then. I'm curious.
Don't get jealous. He's really handsome.
Hey, I have this VHS tape too.
- Really?
- Stephen Chow's A Chinese Odyssey,
Parts one and two.
I placed this sticker in his room
when I was in elementary school.
I didn't even know
this was Sang-yeon's place.
- Really?
- Yeah.
That's Sang-yeon. Adorable, isn't she?
This person…
is Sang-yeon's brother?
Yeah.
Why?
I know him.
Sir, wait! I'd like to get off.
Did something happen?
You've never called this late.
Is this about how I left earlier?
I saw a photo of your brother.
It was you, wasn't it?
You're the one…
who replied to me as Moonee.
Subtitle translation by: Jimin Choi